You know I've spent a great
deal of time contemplating the
nature of addiction and I've
come to a rather startling
conclusion that most people
find quite uncomfortable. What
if the thing that nearly
destroyed you was actually
trying to save you. Now I
realize that sounds absurd.
Perhaps even offensive to those
of you who suffered through the
hell of addiction. But stay
with me for a moment. Because
what I'm about to share with
you might completely transform
how you understand your
struggle. You see I've come to
believe that the addict is not
a weak person, not a moral
failure, not someone who lacks
discipline or character. The
addict is a mystic who's lost
their way. Someone whose soul
is reaching for transcendence
but grasping at the wrong door.
And here's what fascinates me.
What if your addiction wasn't a
curse at all? What if it was a
calling? What if God or the
universe? Or whatever you want
to call the fundamental ground
of being has been speaking to
you all along through this very
suffering. I want to explore
with you today something rather
profound. A complete reframing
of addiction as a form of
divine communication. And by
the end of this you may
discover that you haven't been
cursed. You've been chosen.
Let's begin by understanding
what we're really dealing with
here. Society in its infinite
wisdom. Looks at addiction
through the narrowest possible
lens. Disease, dysfunction,
moral bankruptcy, someone who
can't control themselves.
Someone who needs to fixed,
medicated, rehabilitated, the
whole approach is terribly
mechanical. You're a broken
machine that needs repair. But
this completely misses the
point you see. Because what we
call addiction is actually a
spiritual crisis masquerading
as a chemical dependency. It's
a soul in revolt against the
shallowness of ordinary
existence. It's someone whose
inner being is screaming for
depth for meaning for
connection to something vast
and true. And when that
connection can't be found
through conventional means the
seeking becomes chaotic, self
destructive. I've often said
that the addict is attempting
to reproduce the mystical
experience through chemistry.
You're searching for God in a
bottle, in a pill, in a powder.
Not because you're weak but
because somewhere deep inside
you remember, you remember that
there's more. That ordinary
consciousness, ordinary
reality, ordinary life as we've
constructed it is simply not a
the problem isn't the longing
the longing is absolutely
sacred the problem is the
method you see the substance
becomes a false prophet it
promises heaven but delivers
hell it offers a glimpse of
unity of transcendence and then
snatches it away leaving you
more isolated than before but
here's what's extraordinary god
has been trying to redirect you
all along not through
punishment but through the very
consequences of the path you've
chosen there is a hunger at the
core of addiction that most
people simply cannot fathom and
I want to be very about what
this hunger actually is.
Because it's been terribly
misunderstood. It's not
physical craving. Though that's
how it manifests in the body.
It's not psychological
dependency though that's how
the doctors diagnose it. It's
something far older. Far
deeper. It's what I call
spiritual home sickness. You
see for years you've probably
told yourself the story that
everyone tells addicts. That
you lack will power. That
you're weaker than that if you
just tried harder, if you had
more discipline, more
determination, you could stop.
You could be like those people
who have a drink and walk away.
Who can take it or leave it?
But this is a fundamental
misunderstanding of what's
actually happening. That
insatiable hunger isn't
weakness at all. It's your soul
remembering its true nature.
You're not craving the
substance itself. You're
craving union. You're craving
the dissolution of the illusion
of separation. You're craving
the experience of coming home
to yourself. To the ground of
all being. To the infinite
consciousness that you actually
are beneath all these layers of
identity. Every addict is a
mystic who's forgotten what
they are looking for. The
substance gives you a glimpse
for a few hours. Perhaps even
minutes the walls come down.
The ego quiets. You feel
connected. I complete and then
it ends and you're back in what
I call the prison of ordinary
consciousness so you reach
again not because you're
chasing pleasure but because
you've tasted liberation and
you simply cannot forget what
it feels like your hunger is
absolutely holy you're just
feeding it poison now here's
something quite remarkable
about the process of addiction
it systematically dismantles
the ego addiction takes
everything you thought you were
and reduces it to rubble your
career your relationships, your
self image, your pride, your
certainty about who you are and
what you're capable of. One by
one, every pillar of your
constructed identity falls
away. And while you're in the
midst of this destruction, it
feels like pure annihilation.
It feels like you're losing
everything that matters. Like
you're failing at the
fundamental task of being
human. But there's an ancient
teaching here that we've
forgotten. The false self must
die before the true self can
emerge. You cannot pour into a
cup that's already full. You
cannot build something
authentic on a foundation
that's rotten. What addiction
does you see is strip away
everything that isn't
essential. Every mask, every
pretense, every story you've
told yourself about who you
are, the job title, the
relationship status, the
reputation, the carefully
constructed personality that
you believed was you. And when
all of that is finally stripped
away when you're empty,
hollowed out, to your absolute
essence. That's when there's
finally room for something
real. That's when grace can
enter. That's when your true
nature can reveal itself. You
weren't losing everything.