You're not supposed to ever be
sick. Never. The body is a
miraculous machine that has
been created to take care of
itself and heal itself if we
don't interfere. That you make
yourself sick. And if the mind
is powerful enough to make
yourself sick, it's also
powerful enough to heal you.
First we gotta find out why.
Why did you do this to
yourself? What were you trying
to tell yourself? Every disease
is the body talking to you. Now
cancer of the cases we have
found is caused by suppressed
anger if the person could just
talk about what was bothering
them but they don't they hold
it inside they always say I
don't have any problems you're
the ones with the problems well
that's what I was going to say
to you I mean for someone to
take I mean what you're saying
is they've got to take
responsibility and say no
matter how they feel about
taking the responsibility they
would just go to say about it
yeah and sometimes it goes way
back to childhood they hold it
inside so after a while the
anger begins to turn around
finally eat away organs and
creates cancer.